Can a marriage survive 15 years of marriage?
The Story of Us is a drama, comedy, romance film directed by Rob Reiner.
After 15 years of marriage, Katie and her husband, Ben, have grown apart.
While they keep up the facade of having a contented marriage, mostly to not worry
their children, they aren't happy together and argue frequently.
While the kids are away at camp, Katie and Ben decide to separate and try to reassess
their relationship to see if they should stay together or split up for good.
Ben Jordan, played by Bruce Willis.
Katie Jordan, played by Michelle Pfeiffer.
Stan Kogen, played by Rob Reiner.
Erin Jordan (at Ten), played by Colleen Rennison.
Josh Jordan (at Twelve), played by Jake Sandvig.
Liza, played by Julie Hagerty.
The Story of Us is a 1999 American romantic comedy-drama film directed by Rob Reiner, and
starring Bruce Willis and Michelle Pfeiffer as a couple married for 15 years.
The depiction of the marriage through a series of nonlinear flashbacks is reminiscent of Two for the Road (1967) starring Albert Finney and Audrey Hepburn, while the
"interview" segments featuring characters addressing the camera directly as a therapist are reminiscent of Reiner's previous film When Harry Met Sally...
(1989) starring Billy Crystal and Meg Ryan.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, love of
one's life, summer camp, therapist, family history.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.